<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-16T17:30:03-04:00</updated><id>marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/</id><title type="html">Marcelo Alvarez</title><subtitle>Based in Miami, Florida</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Five Reasons Why Your Ecommerce Site Is So Important For Your Business</title><link href="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/five-reasons-why-your-ecommerce-site-is-so-important-for-your-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five Reasons Why Your Ecommerce Site Is So Important For Your Business" /><published>2019-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/five-reasons-why-your-ecommerce-site-is-so-important-for-your-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/five-reasons-why-your-ecommerce-site-is-so-important-for-your-business/">&lt;p&gt;Most businesses realize the importance of having a good website. Making your business presence known online can be crucial to the success of any business, especially in today’s competitive market. Having a quality website up and running is never more important than around the holidays, when online sales can make up anywhere from 20%-40% of the annual sales of the business. Here are five reasons why your Ecommerce site is so important for your business, not only during the holidays, but at any time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Online Sales Outweigh Sales Made Offline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people enjoy the convenience factor of being able to shop from home, whether it be in their pajamas at 3am, or on their lunch hour from work. Online shopping makes things easy and eliminates a trip to the store to make purchases. Therefore, it is important to have your website updated and running smoothly for customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Websites Influence Purchase Decisions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been shown that many consumers will check out a company’s websites for information about a product they are interested in. It is thought that half of purchases made in stores are the result of consumers having visited the business website first before making the decision to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Holiday Sales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people now do their shopping online for the holidays. By viewing various websites, they are able to compare and decide upon which purchases to make. With so many sales online, if your business falls behind in developing or properly maintaining their Ecommerce site, this could mean a significant loss of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Websites Inspire Shoppers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many shoppers will do a bit of browsing online before deciding to order online or make the trip to the physical store. With the state of the economy, people like to know a bit about the products they are interested in before making their decisions to buy or not to buy. This is why a quality website can benefit any business and increase interest and sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Maximizing Your Ecommerce Site For More Sales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking a few steps to maximize your site to make it an ideal shopping environment, you can greatly increase your potential for sales. Make sure you site is equipped to handle peak times of traffic, such as Black Friday and Cyber Monday. Keep you site running quickly and smoothly so shoppers don’t get frustrated. Make your website offerings easily to search and find for maximum exposure. Stay up to date on website and mobile app information. Take advantage of using social media to promote your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
By realizing the importance of a well running Ecommerce site, your business is sure to gain the traffic and attention it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Here are five reasons why your Ecommerce site is so important for your business, not only during the holidays, but at any time of year.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/images/magento.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Real Estate IDX Integration Systems Can Boost a Realtor’s Business</title><link href="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/how-real-estate-idx-integration-systems-can-boost-a-realtors-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Real Estate IDX Integration Systems Can Boost a Realtor’s Business" /><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/how-real-estate-idx-integration-systems-can-boost-a-realtors-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/how-real-estate-idx-integration-systems-can-boost-a-realtors-business/">&lt;p&gt;In the real estate industry, your website is a very vital aspect of your business. A well designed site helps you to create an excellent brand. Your site can then become the principal resource for home buyers. Fresh leads can be generated faster and this will ultimately boost your property sales. One vital tool that helps your website to achieve all these is real estate IDX integration systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, nearly all major MLS providers allow their members to show property listings from other real estate brokers on their websites via Internet Data Exchange (IDX). This method of feeding your real estate site with updated information from the MLS provider is what is called a real estate IDX integration system. In this post, we will be examining some of the major advantages of IDX integration for websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constantly Updated Property Listings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDX integration gives a realtor the opportunity to provide up-to-date property listings for their customers. The frequency of the updates depends on the type of integration system. FTP IDX will provide 12-hourly updates. The XML-based Real Estate Transaction Standard (RETS) will give you listings that are updated every hour. These updates will make your customers develop more confidence in your website and come back to your site frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excellent Search Engine Optimization (SEO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your real estate site’s page rank can be greatly improved by IDX integration. Due to the frequently updated property listings, your site will be crawled often by Google and other search engines. The landing pages for search results within your site can be optimized by zip code, addresses, subdivision names etc. This will further boost your site’s search engine page rank. Your site would start to show up in the first 1 to 3 pages of search engine result’s pages. This will rapidly increase the visitors to your site and generate more leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased Income Potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDX integration helps to fulfill the ultimate aim of web marketing – to generate more leads and convert them into sales. Through IDX integration, a huge number of properties could be displayed on your website. Property buyers will spend more time on your website. They will search through the listings to locate the kind of property that suits them. Consequently your site will generate more leads which you can easily follow up and convert into actual property sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We connect our client’s websites to the MLS by using IDXpress, with this tool users can search and browse properties in your MLS. Additionally search engines index properties from the MLS on your website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">In the real estate industry, your website is a very vital aspect of your business. A well designed site helps you to create an excellent brand.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/images/idxlogo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Use Twitter to Sell Homes in Just 15 Minutes a Day</title><link href="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/how-to-use-twitter-to-sell-homes-in-just-15-minutes-a-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Use Twitter to Sell Homes in Just 15 Minutes a Day" /><published>2017-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/how-to-use-twitter-to-sell-homes-in-just-15-minutes-a-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/blog/how-to-use-twitter-to-sell-homes-in-just-15-minutes-a-day/">&lt;p&gt;Twitter is everywhere nowadays, and everyone who’s anyone has an account. The network is proving its value to celebrities and politicians, companies and sports stars. In real estate, Twitter can help businesses and potential leads get together, as well as getting their brands seen and – of course – selling properties. Because of its short and sweet nature, just 15 minutes a day spent promoting your business on Twitter can be very effective. You have to do it right, though – work out a plan, and decide what to tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, interesting and engaging tweets will grab your target audience, but annoying and useless tweets will drive potential customers away. Here are some great tips to help you get the results you deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working Out A Strategy
You need to do this first, before you begin tweeting. Ask yourself questions about your business – are you focusing on commercial properties or homes? Are you an established business or just starting out? How would you describe your target market? The right tweets for you depend on how you answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping Subjects Fresh And Varied
Sure, you’re running a real estate business, but put yourself in your customers’ shoes – they don’t want to read about nothing but home listings, so give them a little variety. Give people a reason to follow you, for example by including photos of the local weather conditions, fun questions about movies and holidays, details of local events, etc. Add information about local personalities and where to rent ski equipment, or ask your followers where’s the best place to get a great meal in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweeting questions is good because you build up a two-way relationship, something that will make you the obvious choice when your followers do want to buy a home. Other things you could ask might include their plans for the coming weekend, what they hope to do in the summer, or whether they enjoyed the latest hit movie. Make yourself seem responsive to your audience by both asking these questions and responding to their own tweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Compose-Edit-Reply Schedule
Work out a schedule for your tweeting, and stick to it daily. Research carried out by Bitly, the bookmarking service, shows that it’s best to tweet Monday through Thursday, between one and three in the afternoon. A good tip is to set your phone alarm to ring each day at these times as a reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re ready, spend just five minutes writing your tweet, then another five minutes fine-tuning it to be the best one possible within Twitter’s 140-character limit. Don’t forget that a long username will reduce the space you have for the message itself. Once you’ve posted it, take another five minutes to respond to comments on previous tweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dialogue is a major opportunity for you, so take advantage of it. Make your replies clear and thoughtful, establishing yourself as a leader in the field who it’s valuable to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking Success
A web analytic service like Google Analytics can help you here. When installed, this will let you count the number of visits provided to you via Twitter. On top of this, you’ll get an idea of what visitors do when they reach your site. You can use the service to set up personalized goals – for example, to track whether visitors coming from Twitter submit their contact information or click through to a listing page. Measuring the success – or failure – of the campaigns you conduct through social media is important, so that you know what works best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter Burnout
Otherwise known as writer’s block, this can be solved by listing the subjects you can write about. Take time to read the tweets other real estate agents make, and pick up ideas that way. It’s also great to be creative – some businesses have even set up Twitter profiles for the properties they handle. Don’t be afraid to experiment! But above all, keep that commitment to 15 minutes a day going. When it comes to social media marketing, consistency is vital.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">In the real estate industry, your website is a very vital aspect of your business. A well designed site helps you to create an excellent brand.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="marceloalvarez.github.iomarceloalvarez.github.io/images/twitter.jpg" /></entry></feed>
